How to act as engineer
on the site (2)
Look at the chart of the vendor,
Morton-Thiokol.
At the stage A, he consulted
his immediate boss,
J. R. Kapp.
Mr. Boisjoly is indicated
with pink color.
The chief executive of
engineering
was the vice
president, R. Lund.
Here's A. Thompson,
supervising engineer,
who did the experiment
with Boisjoly.
Boisjoly formed an
unofficial team
with Thompson and
other engineers
to conduct experiments, and
reported the results
to his bosses
numerous times.
He proposed as many as 33
alternative designs
of field joint.
However, the senior
management
did not recognize its
significance.
At the end of July 1985,
they still did not seem
to take any counter-measures.
Getting impatient at
the situation,
Boisjoly wrote a memorandum.
With Kapp's approval,
he handed it
to the chief
executive, Lund.
In the memorandum, Mr.
Boisjoly wrote:
"It is my honest and
very real fear
that if we do not take
immediate action
to dedicate a team to
solve the problem
with the field joint
having the number
one priority,
then we stand in jeopardy of
losing a flight along with
all the launch pad
facilities."
This memorandum
led the company reluctantly
to take action.
In August 1985, an
official team
was formed to
solve the problem,
but, the limited support
from the company resulted in
no substantial solution.
The team proposed 15
experiments,
none of which was realized.
Without support
from the company,
the O-ring Task Force
could do nothing
before December 1985.
Stage C: what would you do
in that situation?
1) Suggest to the vice
president engineer
to provide more resources
to the Task Force;
2) Report to scientific
societies that
the company does not support
Task Force despite of
its safety matter;
3) Record your daily
activities
and observations on
a logbook;
4) Continue working under
the provided condition
following the
company's policy;
5) Take some other actions
These are actions
you may take.