Ethics of science and
technology
When scientists needs to
make ethical decision
Let me
first give you an overview
and goals of this
study program. Science and
technology
produce new values
and give great impact on
society and its environment.
Especially in Japan,
the Great East Japan
earthquake induced
people to recognize both
positive
and negative aspect
of technology.
As active practitioner of
technology,
scientists and engineers
take
distinctive responsibility
for the society.
In this course, we examine
the ethics
that is essential for
engineers of our time
to fulfill their duties.
Various potential ethical
problems
that engineers may face
will be explained through
specific examples,
in order to discuss how we
can
analyze and ethically
examine
these problems. Special
emphasis
will be placed on several
values,
such as safety, that
engineers
should consider highly
important.
Additionally,
based on these studies,
we will consider what kinds
of
ethical capacities and
abilities
are required for engineers
in the 21st century.