The Value
So far we examined
different stakeholders.
Next we discuss
the notion of 'value'.
We have seen that 'value'
plays significant role
in considering the
engineer's ethics.
This will be examined
at many stages
in the following
lectures. Now,
'value', what does this
mean actually?
Generally, Japanese
dictionaries define
'value' as a nature or
property that can be object
of desire or interest
of humankind,
which nevertheless
should be distinct from
personal liking and
preference,
or something useful
and efficient
to fulfill your purpose.
In philosophy,
'value' is defined
as something that should be
universally approved,
regardless of
individual preference,
such as truth,
rightness, and beauty.
Truth, rightness,
and beauty are
basic elements within
the traditional
classification of value.
Truth is an
intellectual value,
and rightness is
a moral value.
And beauty is an
aesthetic value.
There are many others.
Value of procedure
is a criterion
for excellence of procedure.
Religious value is to
judge sacred against evil.
Furthermore,
there's also
commercial value
of products' distribution,
and financial value
of things.
Value judgment is
to estimate something
based on a value system.
Dictionary definition reads:
a value judgment is to judge
something if it is
good or bad,
or the subjective
decision made
on the basis of a value
classification,
such as truth, rightness,
and beauty.
it is worth noting that
the decision is
'subjective'.
In examining the
engineer's ethics,
it is essential to recognize
the subjectivity
of judgment.
Certainly, engineers are
well educated and trained
in objective judgment,
dealing with sharable,.
technical information
such as scientific laws,
theories, and
experimental data.
On the other hand,
engineers' receptivity are
less cultivated towards
subjective values, such as
cultural and
religious values,
it is just like those of
ordinary people. Inevitably,
therefore, engineers tend to
prioritize objective values.
They can be puzzled,
when asked to make
subjective judgment.
However, as we have
discussed,
engineers' ethics
requires you
to design your action,
with your own judgment,
balancing values,
to lead the best solution.
To have a capacity of
'subjective'
judgment is thus essential
as the basis for
ethical judgment.
This is the reason
why we emphasize
the importance of
various values
in this course.