Moreover,  about happiness, Japanese constitution
states in its 13rd sentence.
Mr. Kono, have you ever had
opportunities to think about happiness or well-being
in academic place
like high school
or university.
No, I have never had opportunities to think about it
explicitly
I think.
You have been educated,
And I also attended schools,
but I also have never had chance
to think about well-being
in junior high school,
high school, and university
at all. But
as we have seen,
a mission of tokyo institution of industory
code of conduct in conference
states well-being
clearly in them.
And Aristole also identifies it is important,
and japanese constitution
clearly mention it,
we have never thought about
well-being.
As you say,
We can see the word "happiness" itself
in many places today.
Actually, the word "well-being" is
noticed around the world.
For example, the Pope published
the 10 clues to be happier,
many magazines are interested in
well-being.
But when I start thinking about well-being,
I realize
it is a little bit complicated.
Especially, when we pick up Japan as an example,
it seems strange for me.
How about you, Mr. Kono. What do you think about Japan.
for security, its power,
hospitality..
What do you think.
I personally think
Japan is comfortable country to live,
Personally.
Our GDP is the third highest followed America and China.
Japan is very economically powerful,
and safe, and clean.
I have visited many countries and cities
for the purpose of my business
Japan is really good to live.
But Leicester University in Great Britain
in 2006, made world happiness map,
according to the map,
Japan ranked at 90th in the world.
90th... (laughing)
Yes, 90th. what do you think.
Don't you think it is strange.
(laughing)
OECD, which many countries belong
to economic development ,
international organization
sees countries through GDP, which is macro
index, but
currently, they use
well-being indicators.
Strangely, OECD does not
make rankings about it unlike the Lecester University.
But they shows various items, like
income, housing, and employment.
they research the average,
and how is each country
in OECD.
This is what they do.
They also have some more interesteing,
This is very interesting,
but what I want you to see is
satisfaction of life.
Most countries in OECD are
developed countries, so 59% of people
are satisfied with their life.
Though Japanese is satisfied just only 40%.
This is weird.
Moreover,
Many people taking this course,
their parents
or
their grand parents,
they have worked for the country hard
thanks to those effort,
and thanks to researchers in Tokyo Institutions of Industory,
Thanks to everything I mentioned,
Japan has been becoming rich.
blue line in this figure,
is about Japanese GDP.
it always increases, that is, Japan becomes rich.
it shows.
However, satisfaction of life
orange line shows it,
it decreases.
Strange.
Aeconomist Easterlin
found out and he named it
Paradox of Easterlin.
It means
richer people become,
poorer their satisfaction of life is.
This is paradox.
Yes.
In addition, the rate of suiceide in Japan is
high compared to other developed countries.
Japan is safe and clean, though,
poor satisfaction of life and
many people kill themselves.
it is strange.
And another data says,
the data is from Japanese government,
richness of stuff or richness of heart,
which is more important
the government asks Japanese people every year
Unitil 1980, richness of stuff isb more important
for them than richness of heart.
People think.
However, after 1980,
people think richness of heart is
more important.
How about you, Mr. Kono.
Which do you think
it is more important for you.
I think, as you think,
richness of heart is more important
even though we become economically powerful.
(laughing)
I see.
Then, hou about
money or hapiness.
To become happier,
Do you think money is importan.t
If you do not have money,
you cannot get stuff and become unhappy,
so, I think Money is important.
(laughing)
when I am asked to choose one,
I cannot choose actually.
Many people think they need money
to be happy,
but many research shows
money, hapiness, and satisfaction
do not relate to each other much.
This is a result of statics
conducted in America ,
yearly income 35,000 dollers, if we say 1 doller is worth 100 yen,
people who get less than 3,500,000 yen have
lower happiness in America.
However, income is 35,000 doller to 50,000 doller,
in short, even if your income improve 35,000 to 50,000 dollers,
5,000,000yen to 10,000,000yen,
or over 10,000,000 yen,
hapiness is not improved much.
at least this data says.
Other studies shows
however, other result,
they conclude
we can see the relationship between money and hapiness
a little bit,
So actually, the studies are still going.
Let's see
how American people
answered
when they are asked,
this is multiple choice questions though,
First,
this is the item most people chose,
relationship with their children
Their children make thhem happier,
77% of people chose it.
And friendship makes them happier,
when they contribute to someone,
75% of people chose them.
4th is about husband or wife.
Or relationship with their lover.
This makes people happier, 74 % of people chose it.
So first 4 items are important when we consider
hapiness
first 4 items are what I introduced now.
The answer is the relationships among people
not money or stuff.
This is the answer.
How were these studies about
hapiness or well-being
started.
Of course, studies about hapiness
is made long time ago,
era of Aristole, or further before
in many countries or cultures.
Martin Segman is the first person who started it
scientifically. He is an psychologist in America.
He is a professor in the  University of Pensylvania
He is an experimental psychologist.
He is a chairman in American Psychology Association.
He was elected by three times vote from
the second applicant,
then he was elected as a chairman.
American Psychological Asscociation
is the biggest asscociation
both in America and in the world.
Professor Segliman
will have to
decide which way psychology to go
in the future.
He had to state that.
what do you think Professor Segliman said.
He said various things though,
in his keynote,
what he said
is
APsychology in America contributed to
patients who awere told never be cured
were told never be cured,
and made manuals to diagnose
people who have mental problems,
That is great,
he said.
And Professor Segliman continues
people who have mental issue are at most
20-30 percent,
the rest of 70% live healthier
like Mr. Kono,
Psychology ishould be for hose 70%
can live better,
we should use
intervention,
this is a technical term,
we should use intervention for
helthy people to live better.
He proposed. Professor Segliman
stated he named it positive psychology
to people, then
The history of positive psychology
has officially
started.