Engineer's Ethics (2)
To which social groups
do engineers belong to?
First, engineers belong to
an organization; a
corporation or
an enterprise in
most cases.
This social group has its
ethical principles or
standards of conduct.
They parade a motto
to the society,
showing how they
act and behave.
Second, engineers also
belong to professions,
including academic
societies and
professional associations.
The profession has
its own ethical principles,
which explain
how its members should
act to the society.
And finally,
engineers belong to
the society in a
broader context.
Therefore,
engineers belong to several
social groups,
which can be divided into
six layers, and
each social group has
its own specific
standards of conducts
that should be considered.
It ranges from the values
and standards of an
individual to
that of a constituent member
of the entire humankind.
In this course,
we should pay
particular attention
to the third point:
value and standards
of conduct
as a member of an
occupational group.
Usually this is
directly related
to business ethics and
corporate social
responsibility.
And the fourth point,
value and standards
of conduct
as a member of a group with
professional skills,
is the engineer's ethics.
So far we have discussed the
notion of 'ethics'.
Next, we will consider the
other term of
the 'engineer's ethics',
namely the 'engineering',
because an engineer is the one
who practice the technology.
What is 'engineering'?
There are many definitions
of 'engineer'.
An American Encyclopedia
defines 'engineer' as a
profession.
{The definition in the
encyclopedia shown in English on
the slide}
Traditional
profession includes
medical doctors and lawyers.
Engineers are also regarded
to be
highly intellectual,
professional occupation.
What kind of
professional occupation
is engineer?
Engineering is the
profession
that applies the knowledge
of natural sciences and
various practices to
economically utilize
the materials and forces of
the nature for the benefit
of humankind.
This has to be done
with judgment.
As doctors make
decision about
what kinds of treatment
should be applied to
a patient,
engineers judge
how the natural forces
should be applied for the
benefit of humankind.
Engineers practically
involve themselves
in this process of judgment
and application.
Here arises a big problem.
Even when we accept
this definition I just
explained,
it still remains undefined
what is the benefit of
mankind.
Many people say that
engineering is neutral,
value free.
For instance, they say that
the production of a well-cut
knife is
value free.
But the act of
injure with the knife is
a bad conduct.
While, a creation of
artistic sculpture with the
same knife
is considered to be a good
conduct.
The act of using the knife
can be right or wrong,
but the production of the
knife itself is value free.
This is a popular idea about
engineering.
But, I disagree with this
claim
as it seems not effective
today any more.
Indeed, as the history has
seen,
science technology has
produced a great impact on
humankind.
So, the question of value
arises
already when you decide
which technology you would
employ.
Engineering and values are
rather inseparable from each
other.
What kind of technology
would you face with?
Which technology would you
use?
These decisions reflect the
value of
an individual, corporation
or organization.
Combining the definitions of
the two terms,
'engineering' and 'ethics',
I define 'engineering's
ethics' as follows:
"Engineering's ethics is a
body of normative system
in a social group that
engineers should follow
when they form a judgment on
their conduct
and on related values of
applying their knowledge of
the mathematical and natural
sciences
gained by study, experience,
and practice,
in order to economically
utilize
the materials and forces of
the nature for the benefit
of mankind."
How does the 'engineer's
ethics'
differ from that of general
public?
In this respect,
it is important to notice
that
technology produces a new
value.
Let me give an example.
Fifty or sixty years ago,
if you say you are
interested in
somebody else's internal
organs,
people would say you are
crazy.
However, in the contemporary
society
where we have
immunosuppressive drugs and
organ transplantation
technologies,
somebody else's organs that
used to be valueless
can be valuable for a
patient
suffering from liver
disease,
if the liver would be
compatible
to his/her body.
Thus,
technology gave a new value
to human body's organs.
Another example.
In 1932, James Chadwick
at the Cavendish Laboratory
of
the University of Cambridge
discovered the neutron.
Before his discovery,
an atom with a big nucleus
emitting natural radiation,
such as uranium,
had been regarded
worth a subject of
scientific study.
But no one recognized its
other potential values.
However, once Leo Szilard
and
his fellow physicists
discovered
the mechanism of neutron
chain reaction,
which occurs when one single
nuclear reaction causes
one or more subsequent
nuclear reactions,
scientists realized
they could apply
this mechanism of releasing
vast quantities of energy
using neutrons to other
purposes,
such as nuclear weapons.
Therefore,
science and technology
produce
a new value,
and only engineers
working in the forefront
can recognize the emergence
of
this new value.
And it is only engineers
who can design appropriate
acts
and conducts how to use the
innovative technology,
carefully balancing between
the new and existing values.
In this regard, engineer's
ethics has
a particular responsibility.