When you talk about learning
science and engineering ethics
do you only mean
learning certain rules such as
you must not do this
or you must do that?
Is this what learning ethics all about?
I think that there are many people who
have this kind of idea about ethics.
But there is definitely more than that.
First of all, what is ethics, what constitutes ethical judgement?
This is what I'd also like you
to think about.
Please take a look at this slide.
When I talk about the ethics of science
or ethics of technology
I imagine the image of a balance like this.
As Mr. Kono said earlier, many people think that
ethics is about norms and rules
that must be adhered to and preserved.
I'm aware that this is
a very common preconception.
However, in this course,
I would like you to step out of these restrictive notions.
Instead, think about ethics as
a sort of balance, or a balance of values.
This is what I will be talking about.
When we analyse how to make ethical judgement
we can see that it is actually about
finding a balance between various issues.
This is how I see it.
For example, consider about engineers and technicians
in the course of their daily work they
need to take into account in many different values.
The most important one is, of course...
Safety, but that is not all.
This is not determined by only safety alone.
There are other concerns, such as cost
or deadlines, or whether to try a new design.
Or a product's durability.
There are many factors we can assign value to.
We seek a balance between these values
when making decisions.
Making an ethical decision
means making the right call.
Making an unethical decision
means making an inappropriate choice.
Finding the correct balance between values
is a creative process.
It requires an imaginative approach.
Making ethical considerations
means seeking the right balance
in the decision-making process.
Now, I have been talking about values.
The actual concept of values
will be the key throughout the course
so please keep that in mind.
Now that this is clear
I would like to start the lecture.
Yes, please go ahead.