Could you please
explain the importance of ethics
not just in general
but as it related to science and technology?
In a nutshell, the relationship between science and technology
and society is changing in significant ways.
To make it clearer,
let me give you
a little quiz.
Do you know what happened
on the four dates shown on this slide?
Let's see...
December 2nd, 1942, I think there was
there was something related to World War 2.
Right, there is some connection with the war.
However, there would be no exaggeration
to say that this is the most important day
in the history of mankind.
On that day, research on nuclear weapons began,
led by the United States and the United Kingdom.
It was known as
the Manhattan Project.
Enrico Fermi who fled from Italy
was one of the scientists
working on this project.
A secret laboratory, Metallurgical Laboratory,
was established at the University of Chicago
with a team of scientists.
It was the day of the first successful
controlled nuclear fission chain reaction.
In other words, that day marks the start of the Atomic Age.
Why is this related to ethics?
I will talk about this more later,
but ethics, in principle,
is a behavioural science.
If a behaviour or action is not possible
then it does not lead to ethical problems.
For example, time travel.
Currently, time travel is impossible for us.
We do not have a time machine that would let us travel in time.
So, concerns about whether time travel would be good or not
may be an interesting subject in
the field of science fiction, such as comics.
But right now, time travel is still impossible for us.
So, it does not present any
ethical problems for us to solve.
Since it is an action we simply cannot perform.
But on December 2nd, 1942
mankind became capable of
using atomic energy.
From that day, we gained
that new ability.
Why does it matter? Well, before that day
even if a leader of some country was planning
to obliterate mankind
they had no physical means to do it.
Even if they sprayed poison gas worldwide
it would not be enough to annihilate the human race.
But on December 2nd, 1942
we obtained a new source of tremendous energy
unlike anything we had known ever before.
atomic energy
And with it, we unlocked the possibility
to annihilate our own kind.
From that day
we have a new ethical issue to face.
The issue of whether it would be right or wrong
to obliterate mankind.
That day marks
a momentous change in our world.
That's right. So, from my point of view
December 2nd, 1942
is the most memorable day
in human history.
Indeed. I know what happened on the next date, September 11th, 2001.
That's right.
A series of terrorist attacks took place then, as you know.
But what significance did they have?
You see,
scientists acting in good will, people like you,
engineers and technicians
used their knowledge to create a wonderful invention.
A passenger plane.
A plane designed to transport
as many people as possible, as fast as possible,
as far as possible, with comfort.
It was a good invention, but someone used it for a different purpose
and it leads to tragedy.
It showed us that an individual or a small group
are able to wage war
even against a super power like the USA,
or possibly even the whole world.
There is a bright and a dark side to science and technology.
This is what I mean by dual-use technology.
And it was illustrated for us by events that happened in front of our eyes.
The dual use of technology has been much discussed
by historians of science, scientists,
philosophers of science.
It was the topic in many debates.
But then, it became reality.
We saw it with our own eyes
on the screens of TVs,
in our living rooms.
So that's what September 11th, 2001 has taught us.
Next is June 13th, 2010.
I'm not sure about this one.
I've been talking about unsettling events thus far
but this time it is a positive one that I'd like to mention.
On that day the Japanese asteroid probe Hayabusa
which was sent to the asteroid Itokawa
successfully landed back on Earth.
So, what did we learn
on that day?
We learned that our physical range of actions
can extend as far as 6 billion kilometres away from earth.
This is definitely something to be pleased with.
That day illustrated
the good side of science and technology.
I see. Lastly, we have March 11th, 2011.
It was a very memorable day
to all of us.
Yes. As I mentioned earlier,
a big earthquake occurred along Japan’s north-east Pacific coast.
An earthquake of the magnitude 9.0
was registered for the first time in Japan.
As you know,
the earthquake was followed by a tsunami
which in turn caused an accident at a nuclear power plant.
Of course, the technical staff
working at that power plant
made the utmost effort
to ensure safety.
However, no matter how many precautions we make,
even if they seem to be working fine,
the forces of nature are so powerful
we can lose control of facilities.
This is what was made clear to us that day.