The examples that I've talked about so far
focus on examples related to
science, technology, and society.
The fact that human relations are getting complicated
is something you have probably realised as well.
In the history of mankind
modern science and technology's role in human society
has never been more impactful than at any other era.
That's probably something we can say.
What we now call Science and Technology
are words that have clear definition but
behind Science and Technology, there are always humans that's how it is
There are either experts who are involved or organisations
involved
So these Science and Technology experts
they work within an organisation that makes decisions and
these actions and their consequences
can have serious impact on society and the environment.
We are in times when there are such a possibilities
this is something that we need to recognise
So in order to help you to understand this better,
some examples were raised.