Seven Steps Guide 4
Now, let us give a test
on the actions we
have listed
in the mini-case.
Considering the
limitation of time,
we will examine their
ethical value
through the
Reversibility test and
the Universalization test.
How do you evaluate
the action
with the Reversibility test?
Well, if my grand
parents are
working in farming
downriver,
I doubt if I follow
the chief manager's
instruction.
Or, you can imagine
if your parents are perhaps
living downstream.
Then, at least you cannot
blindly obey the
instruction.
That's right. The
reversibility test reveals
that the Action Plan
1, following
the chief's instruction and
releasing the contents
to river, to be ethical
inappropriate.
Now, how about with the
Universalization test?
If all the engineers
in the world would
only follow the instruction,
despite having
concern on the harm
it does to the environment,
then what happens?
Engineers will lose
people's trust,
and inconsistencies
arise in the society.
Therefore, the act of
obeying the chief's
instruction blindly,
is ethically denied also
by the
universalization test.
Yes. As we have seen,
in the Step 5,
you will examine ethical
appropriateness of
your action through
various tests.
I believe, just knowing the
conceptual framework
of the six tests helps
a lot for us
to design our
behavior as engineer.
Indeed, the ethic tests are
introduced to corporate
activities as a way
to encourage employee's
ethical behaviors.
Corporations such as
Lockheed Martin
and Texas Instruments
have their
own ethics tests.
Here, I will
briefly refer to
the ethics test of the
Texas Instrument,
a corporation well known
for its good ethical
practices.
The Texas Instrument's
ethics quick test lists
the following questions:
'Does the action legal?',
'Does it comply
with the Texas
Instruments' values?',
'If you do it,
will you feel bad?',
'How will it look in
the newspaper?'
and 'If you know it's wrong,
don't do it!'
Beneath the quick
test, it reads:
if you are uncertain
about something,
consult it with your boss
or Ethics Contact
till you are fully
convinced.
The ethical tests are
printed on a card,
which every employee of
Texas Instruments is
carrying at all times.
Yes, an employee of the
company brings,
besides his/her
employee ID card,
an ethic card.
On the front side you
read the ethical code
of the company, and the
quick test stands
on the back.
Now, in the Step 6,
you will review
your measure based on
steps 1 to 5.
You make a final
choice based on
the former
considerations on
possible actions
you may take.
It is also possible
a completely different
option comes
under consideration
at this point.
When you make the
final decision
at step 6, you might
think you have done
through the whole process
of decision-making.
However, the Seven
step guide has
one more important step,
step 7.
In the step 7,
you consider how
you could reduce
the likelihood that
you will need
to make a similar
decision again.
You should also think how
you could solve
the problem of your
situation
and improve your
organization,
by re-examining
the former steps
from 1 to 6.
What is the significance
of the step 7?
One thing is, of course,
it is beneficial to
think once again
if it is really good to
take that action.
But more important
than that,
it is significant to
work out a plan
how you could avoid falling
in a similar situation.
Of course it is
possible that
there would be nothing
you could do.
But, there might be a way to
change the organization
to prevent the
problem. For instance,
improving the atmosphere at
your workplace
to encourage employees
to consult difficult
situations with others,
or providing better support
from the ethics consultant,
this would change the
whole situation.
It is thus an essential step
to design measures
to prevent falling in a
similar ethical problem.
Furthermore, re-examining
your situation
not only from a micro
but from a macro
point of view
leads you to consider
in which way
the organizations or
systems should change.
Referring to the 4 levels of
engineering ethics
we have studied in the
beginning of this class,
you can say that the
step 7 is where
you move from the
micro viewpoint
to the mezzo point of view.
In a real situation,
you might have not
enough time
to follow the whole steps.
However, following the 7
Steps guide,
a longer, careful
consideration is crucial,
especially for a
prevailing problem
that may cause an
enormous impact.
The guide is also
helpful to look back
on actions you took.
Of course, the 7
Steps guide cannot
solve all the ethical
problems.
It is just a guideline
you can follow,
which enables you to
carefully consider
before you come to a
decision
how you act.
However, it is helpful
not to jump to an
impulsive conclusion
but to think thoroughly,
even when you have to make
an ethical decision
in a complicated situation.
You can improve your ability
in ethical decision-making
by examining
different previous cases
according to the guideline
and by experiencing
the decision-making
processes
by yourself.
I want you to think about,
what if you were
in these cases,
how you could make your
ethical decision.