So, if we think of humanity on the scale of the Cosmic Calendar,
we have created science and technology
merely a second ago.
One second in the Cosmic Calendar
is about 475 years, as I said before.
Now think of the last 0.25 seconds.
A quarter of a second, the modern times.
Think of what mankind has achieved
in the 20th century.
Here on this slide we have
a list of the greatest technological achievements
from the 20th century,
compiled by the United States National Academy of Engineering. So this is the list.
We, humans, have been alive for only one second in the Cosmic Calendar,
managed to create these technologies
within a quarter of a second.
At the same time,
we have potentially gained the knowledge and ability
that would enable us to destroy Earth.
Do you see what I mean?
There are always two sides to a coin.
Precisely. Now please take a look
at the next slide.
This is a picture of cities on the Earth
taken by NASA.
Although it is a beautiful sight
energy is necessary to produce all this light.
How long will this light continue to glimmer
on Earth with its finite resources?
In other words, how long can our technological civilisation
continue to thrive and progress?
This is something to think about.
On to the next slide...
This graph shows the changes in our population
and energy demand from the year 1800.
At the end of the 19th century there were 1.7 billion people.
As for the energy demand
it would be equivalent to
500 million tons of oil per year.
However, only 100 years since then,
only 0.25 seconds
on the Cosmic Calendar scale,
in the year 2000, our population was about 6 billion.
And now it is over 7 billion.
Our energy consumption in the year 2000
was about 9.2 billion tons of oil a year.
Within just a century,
less than a quarter second in the Cosmic Calendar,
our population quadrupled, and energy consumption increased 18 times.
That is quite rapid.
The per capita energy consumption
rose about 5 times.
The energy consumption
is not evenly distributed across the world.
It has not risen that much for people
in the developing countries that account for
the majority of the world's population.
This huge rise in energy consumption
is caused by the people of developed countries
such as Japan, the USA
and European countries.
In the light of this,
it is easy to see why the Earth quickly became
so polluted in the 20th century.
If developing countries continue to industrialize
and increase their energy consumption
just like the already developed countries had done,
we can easily imagine how disastrous
that might be.
Well, the Cosmic Calendar
illustrates the greatness of mankind
but it also puts our existence into perspective
by showing just how brief
our history on this planet is.
It gives us a frame of reference.
Think from this perspective about
the engineers and scientists who have to tackle ethical problems
and about the regulations they need to abide by.
These established rules
may seem set in stone
and impossible to change.
People think this is just how it is.
It is quite common
to think this way.
But looking at it from the broad perspective
there is nothing that definitely cannot be changed.
These issues are merely
a brief local phenomenon.
The bigger perspective lets us see that
anything can be changed if you set your mind to it.
It gives us courage
to act.
Well, then, what about the future?
Our future?
We're in the 21st century now.
In Cosmic Calendar terms the 21st century
is less than a quarter of a second.
Within this time, how should
the relationship between science and society develop?
Or how, in what way
should we keep science and technology
under control?
I often use this picture
of a race car.
It is precisely because it's a time when humanity depends on technology
that engineers and scientists are expected to
make ethical decisions based on the macro point of view,
on a broad perspective.
And why is that the case?
Technology was born
only a second ago in the Cosmic Calendar.
Let me give you a metaphor.
At that time we, humans,
were like a driver
that just got a driver’s license.
Having just stepped outside,
the brand new license in hand,
the freshly-minted driver comes across a race car.
This car is a metaphor for technology.
Normally, rookie drivers
do not get to drive race cars just like that.
It is quite scary to imagine what might happen if they did.
But our driver finds this race car with its engine on,
everything in gear, ready to go.
The tank is full of petrol.
The road ahead is unusually wide.
The driver tentatively steps on the accelerator.
The racing car, the technology,
starts and gains momentum.
Mankind sees technology as an amazing thing
and lets it pick up more and more speed.
Our racing car
keeps going faster and faster.
We entered the second half of the 20th century
going at high speed.
We can not see what the future might hold.
Checking the fuel tank,
looking at the fuel gauge,
we notice we're running out of gas.
We cannot see what's ahead.
Maybe the road
isn't straight.
Maybe we're approaching a corner.
Maybe it's a hairpin corner.
And maybe what lies ahead is a wall.
This is the situation we're in.
We have never before
tried to step on the brake
of the racing car that is technology.
Neither have we used the steering wheel.
We're just greenhorns
who have only been pushing down on the accelerator.
This is how we can describe our current situation.
This is the picture we get
when we look from the macro perspective,
from the perspective of time.
So how should the present-day
scientists and engineers act,
what guidelines should they use
to make decisions?
Sometimes thinking from such a big perspective,
from the macro perspective,
will let you see things more clearly,
and give you new ideas.
I see, that makes sense!