Professor, if we classify the story into four levels,
Basically it was a story on a Macro level
we can think about it that way, except
when you think about it on other levels
What can we say about it?
On a meso level,
Although this is related to organizations and institutions,
regarding this point as well, since the 1990s,
big changes have been occurring.
On this matter,
information becomes more detailed at this point,
so it's better to read it in text format, but
briefly speaking,
for someone to be an internationally qualified engineer
what kind of abilities should this person possess?
These things were discussed in the 1990's,
during engineering training, what is always required is
the train engineers with technological capabilities.
This is compulsory training.
And the reason, is what we spoke about earlier
the engineers make the decisions and
judgment, actions and behaviours based on it
while it has become a major influence on human society.
Ethical judgment ability is also
something that should be compulsory for internationally qualified engineers.
It is a basic ability
based upon a common understanding in every country in this world.
That is why now, the ethics of the technology
if we question it, should be questioned on a meso level
I think I can say that.
Finally, how about at the micro level?
This is especially the case for Japan, but in the 1990's,
Along with the previous meso, around the second half of the mid-1990s,
In 1995, I'm not sure if you
remember Mr. Kono,
For example, the followers of Aum Shinrikyo
released poisonous gas in the subways,
This kind of incident happened.
Because of that, well trained people with excellent education
injured or killed innocent people using poison gas
Such terrorist acts were committed.
And we want to question why
such an incident occurred.
This was not an isolated incident,
Just as you see in this timeline,
every year, technical people
and their organisations are involved in various incidences,
Such technology ethics,
cases related to technology ethics occur frequently.
This is the ethics of engineers on a micro level,
showing the importance of the engineer’s ethical judgment ability.
I believe this is in the background from which we should start our next discussions.