Learning from examples of past failed case studies
we can Leverage the lessons learnt
to test our own ethical judgment.
Isn't that an important thing?
Yes, of course it is very important
If we say that until now, most cases are related to the
education of ethics
based on the happenings in the past
There were various scandals
and incidents that happened
When we decide, let's not do this
sort of thing
Let's decide not to do this sort of thing
There are many methods to emphasize
this in education
But then, in fact, it only looks at ethics from one point of view
that's what I believe is happening
As I mentioned at the beginning of today's lecture
things that must be done and things that must be protected
placing emphasis on these things
in order to ensure that incidents and
scandals do not happen.
This is what we normally
call preventive ethics.
This is certainly important.
This is certainly and surely required in ethics education
when we think about ethics.
This standpoint of preventive ethics is important.
Even in education, teaching preventive ethics
needs to be done properly.
Although this is certain
when considering the original meaning of ethics.
We come to the second half of this subject
let's discuss ethics more slowly
It is not about something that engineers must adhere to.
What can engineers do?
What is the good that can be done,
when we think in this way
This refers to aspirational ethics.
Aspirational ethics
as we would call it.
This is also another important aspect of ethics.
Even though I started talking about it earlier
when we talk about why this is so.
The original meaning of ethics is
to live well and to do things that allow us to live well
What kind of decision should we make
and how should we act?
Thinking in this way involves ethics
As I said before
preventive ethics emphasizes what should not be done.
For example, when we look at
the Code of Ethics from various educational bodies
according to certain statistics, for example in America
there is the
Professional Engineers Association.
The provisions of the code written in the Code of Ethics
80% of them are passive or prohibitions
these are the types of codes being used
that's what was reported.
But as I said earlier
when we return to the original meaning of ethics
it is about what we need to do in order to live well.
When we look at ethics from the viewpoint of
such intentions,
it is not about what engineers cannot do
but what we should aim to develop
or what a company should seek as their goals.
What needs to be developed or
how engineers and corporations should behave
also how to make better decisions and practices
with active intentions.
The existence of such ethics then surfaces.
This kind of intellectual act
as I mentioned earlier,
I call it “aspirational ethics"
Although there is such a subject
Of course, we must work on Preventive Ethics, but
we should adopt the viewpoint of aspirational ethics.
This new type of ethics
is a subject on Science and Technology Ethics
I hope you can think about it this way.