Value and Code of
Ethics of Engineers 2
This is Article 1 of
the fundamental
canons of ethics
for engineer.
It is a prominent principle
stated in the first line
of many code of ethics.
It reads:
'Engineers shall hold
paramount the safety,
health and welfare
of the public in
the performance
of their professional duties."
Public safety,
health, and well-being are
the most important values
for engineers.
At the same time,
the Article 4 of
the fundamental
canons states that
'engineers shall act
in professional matters
for each employer or client
as faithful agents
or trustees, (...)'.
Code of ethics stipulates
many other values.
For instance, it states
engineer shall avoid
conflicts of interest.
Many others, such as safety,
are prescribed in the codes.
Now, let's look
at the history
of code of ethics for
engineers in Japan.
The first code of
ethics in Japan was
established by a society
of civil engineers
in 1938.
It was called as
'the principles and
code of practices for
civil engineer'.
It stated engineer's dignity
and code of practices.
Considering it was established
as early as in 1938,
it was remarkably
well formulated,
thanks to the leadership
of Akira Aoyama.
Aoyama was a renowned
civil engineer worked for
the Home Ministry.
He became the 23rd president
of Japan Society of Civil
Engineers.
Influenced by
Kanzo Uchiyama,
Aoyama developed his career
in the United States
and worked on the Panama
Canal construction.
Aoki was an
unprecedented engineer
with international
perspective
and practical experience.
Aoki considered
civil engineering as
essential driving force for
the cultural development.
Referring to the
examples in the U.S.,
he constituted a noble
and lofty code of ethics.
He proposed the draft
in 1933, which was officially
approved by the society
in 1938. However,
in the time of
chauvinistic nationalism
fueled by the
Sino-Japanese war
and the Pacific war,
Aoki's code of ethics
did not receive
recognitions,
even in the society
until recently.
The code had
a very limited impact
on Japanese civil engineers.
In 1950's, when Japan entered
the post-war
restoration period,
after the model of
consulting engineer
in the U. S.,
the qualification law
of professional engineer
was established
in Japan in 1957,
with the aim of
putting their
professional skills
for the development of
national industry.
Following the
qualification systems
such as consulting engineer,
professional engineer
in the U.S. and Europe,
chartered engineer
in the U.K.,
the law officially
prescribed
the specific qualification
for Japanese
consulting engineer.
In 1961,
the Institution of
Professional Engineers
established the
code of ethics
for engineers and
their practices.
This code of ethics,
however,
did not receive
much recognition,
neither.
Because of the
small number of
qualified engineers,
it didn't
have prevailing impact
to the whole country.
After 80 years since the
establishment in the U.S,
the first modern code
of ethics for
Japanese engineer
was established
in 1996. The international
information science
associations criticized
only societies in
Japan and Korea among
all those in the world
have no code of ethics.
Receiving the pressure from
international community,
the Information Processing
Society of Japan
quickly established
their code of ethics.
As the relationship between
science and society changes,
major scientific societies
and associations
followed to establish
code of ethics,
and revised it regularly.
It is important for you
to read and examine
the code of ethics
prescribed by scientific
societies and associations
in your relevant field,
to study and consider
what kinds of values
are emphasized
in your field of engineering.