So, there are various theories,
let's pick up on example
psychological well-being, which is
proposed by Carol Riff from Wisconsin University,
says there are six aspects,
the other example is from Gallup,
which conducts statics across the world,
we use their data,
well-being Tom Ruth proposes,
it is like inclusive well-being.
well-being begins from carrier,
to community.
This is he proposed.
We can see more idea about well-being,
the most powerful and popular model
among us is
Segliman's PERMA model.
Segliman says well-being is a concept,
so we cannot measure it with one index.
For example,
just as we cannot judge the weather in Tokyo
with one index,
No one cannot measure well-being
with one index. However,
I think there would be a factor structuring well-being.
I think it is measurable.
There might be
some measurable factors of well-being
at least, there are five,
according to Segliman.
One is Positive emotion, fun, happy,
comfortable, something like that.
People feel well-being
when they are fun, happy, and comfortable
I think.
And then, let's talk about ebgagement,
this word also cannot fit any Japanese words,
like immersion, people concentrate on work
forgetting time, concentrate on sports or artistic activities,
when people concentrate on something,
that is the situation he called engagement.
People feel happiness during engagement.
So called in flow,
in zone for athlete.
the situation like that.
This relates to well-being.
Third, about positive relationships,
that is human relationships.
when people have worries,
some call to someone at 3 midnight.
Or when people have their friends
who they can share fun,happiness,
or comfort with,
they feel well-being.
Absolutely right.
And move on to fourth, this is important,
Meaning, this is gained
when people contribute to someone precious fot them,
well-being is
It is said that
satisfaction is an important factor.
In the end, about achievement.
achieving something, whatever,
job, or making plastic models,
and complete them, this is
a kind of achievement.
It is said that
achievement relates to well-being much.
The most important factor is meaning,
according to some expertise, what do you think.
Do you Mr. Kono think
you can gain well-being
when you contribute to someone
precious.
I think it is convincible that meaning
relates to hapiness when you can believe
your action or your existence has meanings.
According to an investigation,
People who are satisfied with their life has high number of meaning,
that is, they feel meaning strongly.
right.
Also, meaning is larger than well-being
and it affects longer period,
Positive psychology revealed
these outcomes.
Based on that,
I could say,
as I told,
Principle of technicians is public safe, health,
and contribution to welfare, we should focus on these.
This is a roll model
made by people around the world.
People who can follow the principle can be
a ethical technician.
I think.
And, positive psychology,
scientific outcomes of positive psychology
showed meaning, that is,
contributing to someone precious,
it can give people well-being ,
which lasts long time
and strongly.
Scientific study revealed this.
so, principle in the beginning,
the rule and the outcome tell us
something that
technicians can give bigger welfare
by working with ethic,
providing well-being,
They themselves can live better,
I mean they can be happier.
I can say that.
This is the engineering ethic 2.0
This is the new idea of engineering ethic,
what do you think, Mr. Kono.
It is way better than version 1.0 (laughing)
I think I can be motivated.
It's my pleasure.
Thank you for your comment.
Ok, then let's summarize
what I talked in the second half.
First, ethics does not mean you do not do this,
do not do that, like preventive ethics,
it means  live better and happier.
what is well-being,
what can I do,
it is important to think these things
to behave.
Moreover,
ethics is
aspirational ethics.
knowledge and ability to judge are for engineers,
or for their relatives,
marginal, for example,
neither application nor app,
I know we need  superior
app to work well, though,
what for you do it,
relating to OS systems,
even if you have good apps,
you cannot work well without OS.
right.
So ethics is like
core talent of engineers,in other word,
it is like OS.
And,
principle of engineering ethics, public safety,
health, welfare, this is ethical engineer,
from the perspective of positive psychology,
people can gain  well-being
when they have meaningful work,
contribute to someone precious,
subjective and long lasting well-being,
that is, by working with ethics,
people can give their contribution and welfare to society,
and they themselves can be happier,
live better.
This is what I want you to remind
through this lecture.