Seven-Step Guide 3
In the previous step,
we learned
how to examine listed
possible actions.
In this examination,
we use several 'tests'.
These tests are called
'ethic tests'.
It is to consider validity
and propriety of
certain actions.
This tests also reveals
ethically
inappropriate actions.
First, let me explain about
the Reversibility Test.
In the reversibility test,
you will consider
if you would make the
same decision,
even if you were in
the position
who would be
directly affected
by the action you are
about to take.
For example,
if the result of your action
you are taking will give
negative influence
on your health and safety,
you may not to make
such an decision.
If so, the action is
ethically not appropriate.
It is same as the
golden rule that
you should not do something
you don't want to be done.
Reversibility Test is thus also
called as the Golden Rule Test.
The golden rule is a basic
moral principle
shared by major
religions in the world.
In Christianity, it
is said that
'one should treat others as
one would like others
to treat oneself.'
In Confucianism, they say
'one should not treat others
in ways that one would not
like to be treated.'
Besides Reversibility Test,
can we do some
additional tests?
Yes. In the following part,
I will explain a few
more ethical tests.
Let's look at the
'Universalization Test'.
The Universalization
Test is based on
Immanuel Kant's ethical
theory of duty.
In his famous
deontological ethics,
Kant argued that
ethical thinking
fundamentally seeks
for universality,
and the primary formal
requirements
for ethics is to be
universal.
Therefore, ethical
value of an act
can be measured by
its universalizability,
if you can universalize
it or not.
Based on this
Kantian ethics,
the Universalization
Test considers:
what if 'everybody'
took the action
that you are about
to conduct?
In other words, you
universalize the action.
If, as a consequence of
the action taken by
everybody,
contradictions and
inconsistency
may occur within
the society,
then the action is
ethically inappropriate.
Let's take an example of
lying or breaking promise.
Let's test the case if you
decide, for some reason,
to break your promise
with friend.
What if everybody
would break promises?
Then, the society
does not function.
Thus, breaking promises is
an ethically
inappropriate behavior.
Universalization Test is
a useful way of judging
appropriateness of action.
Another useful measure is.
the Virtue Test. It is
less well-known
but quite important.
The Virtue Test is based on
the virtue ethics
originated by
ancient Greek philosophers
such as Aristotle.
Virtue ethics examine
not an action
in a certain situation
but the actor itself.
You think if the action
you are taking is
appropriate to a person
you want to be liked.
You also examine,
whether the action leads you
to live a good
life you wish.
In Aristotle's ethics,.
the 'good life' means
the highest human good, or
'eudaemonia'.
The Greek word
'eudaemonia' is
often translated as
'happiness',
but it is better said as
'well-being'.
In business ethics,
the Virtue Test is called
as 'mirror test'.
You think yourself,
how you feel when
you look at
your face in the mirror
the next morning after
you have conducted a
certain action.