Seven Step Guide part 2
Let's proceed to step 1.
Step 1 is to clarify ethical issues
In this step, it is important to clarify what kind of problems you are facing
In this case study,  if you follow the manager's order
And if for instance it contains something bad for the environment
we will not meet the value held for public safety.
At the same time, we can not meet the expected organizational loyalty and value
If you do not follow the instructions given by your boss.
You are facing what is called the
"Dilemma Problem."
As you mentioned, ethical issue can be classified into two types.
The dilemma problem and demarcation problem.
Yes, that is correct.
Try using easy words to explain the problem that you are facing
without thinking about the dilemma being faced.
I think this is the most important thing to do.
Step 2 is considering facts
Of course, there are known facts,
unclear facts as well as points of speculation
clarifying and considering which facts are needed to examine ethical issues.
In this mini case, the facts known are clear.
As for a fact to be considered such as what is the
the content of the drum. What is inside ?
Whether the drum belongs to the company
Whether or not there is another method to find out what the contents are.
Has the company experienced a similar case in the past
Whether the section chief only  knows about this fact
These issues need to be investigated.
In Step 3
In this step, you are required to identify the relevant factors.
Professor, what sort of factors should be taken into consideration
Firstly, those who will be affected by your decision-making.
The stakeholders.
What type of stakeholders are out there?
You need to think about it
and values which the stakeholders hold.
It is necessary to think  what the stakeholders are considering.
In addition, there are relevant laws
What kind of related laws exist
must be determined.
there are many academic societies related to specific fields
There you should also refer to such codes of ethic they have.
Therefore, as an Engineer it is important to understand what the values are
and is it necessary to re-organize the values again.
In the case of this mini case, the stakeholders are the chief and yourself.
In addition, your  family, colleagues,
Residents living by the basin of the river, or
supervisors managing the rivers such as
local governments and or departments
Also, such as the ministries of the government  and agencies.
All these may be referred to as stakeholders.
I think that can be said. The fact is
when you think how the actions you take
can have an impact on the environment governed by laws and regulations in the region
I think it is an important factor as well.
Given the guide, step 4 contains the list.
According to Prof. Davis, there should be at least five action options.
I agree. Coming up with five can be quite difficult.
The important point here is to think about it
for example, to follow or to not follow instructions.
Rather
Based on the information obtained in the previous step
consider who to consult with, what should you say,...
Now let's list some of the action plans
from the previous case study.
Well Kono-san, could you think of the possible actions?
Firstly, be obedient to the group leader and follow his/her instructions and
empty the contents inside the drums without thinking
The contents of the drums to group leader, the facts
Second, confirm what is inside the drums with the group leader.
Follow instructions accordingly if there are no issues.
Third, follow the boss' instructions, while confirming facts later.
Fourth, explain about environmental pollution
After having explained to the boss, about the contents of the drums
follow instructions if there is no problem but
If there is likely to be a problem
try to convince the boss to reconsider.
If the group leader does not respond to counter argument, refuse to follow the instruction.
Consult with colleagues if you are given the cold shoulder.
I think this can be an option as well.
I agree. Alternatively, say you cannot do it due to injury or run away, for example.
If it necessary, there are usually a number of things and alternatives to consider given a particular situation.