Even more, in buisiness field.
Positive psychology is used.
Called Zappos, on the internet, originally
there is a company which sells shoes
,it has developed like skyscraper.
The CEO of the company, Tony Jay
runs the company using positive psychology
and it leads the company's sccess clearly.
Let's see Google
Google has Google University in their company for employees' training
In the system,
the most popular subject is
the program, called Search Inside Yourself
Eh,
This is also
based on positive psychology.
Moreover, local government also tries to use
positive psychology,
I heard.
In Australia,
you know the state of south Australia,
of which Adelede is the capita.l
Then The state of South Australia ,
Dr. Seligman visited there, and
the problem the state has, actually industrial structure
is changing slowly
To solve the problem,
I asked him
what I can do.
Then he proposed
to make strategies to increase well-being in entire state,
the government should lead those strategies.
That what he said to me, and I proposed his idea to the government.
Then, the state of south Australia
made a lab tomeasuring well-being and resilience,
they actually measured well being
and decided to take in positive education,
which is based on positive psychology,
they launched some actual strategies to increase well-being in entire of the state.
This is a report made by
officials in Great Britain,
including various good practices
about training of mindfulness.
The report says with these good practices supported by science
they try to increase well-being
in Great Britain.
In addition, the United Nations set World Happy Day
on March 20, in 2011.
After 2011, almost every year,
countries participating in the United Nation measure their well-being
and apply the data to their strategy making.
That's what the report meant.
This is the latest investigation,
the data of well-being from 2013 to 2015 is on it, though,
Sadly, Japan is on 53th (laughing).
Achievement of the study about positive psychology is
used for various purpose.
I think that is true. However,
Are there any theory about well-being or hapiness
already?
Are there any theory systems?
As I told you,
The study about well-being started
just 10 years ago.
Therefore, there have not been theories and models,
like anyone can accept.
Mr. Kono, sorry for asking suddenly,
I heard you studied the history of science as well.
Do you know what Aristotle believed
cosmo was made by?
Or,where Aristle believed  the center of cosmo.
Do you remember that.
Aristle devided ceiling into ground,
he said ground is made by soil, water, air, and fire,
so called the classical element theory,
and he thought the center of cosmo is the Earth.
Exactly, that's right. And his thought
is told in Greece and Rome
even after Alistle passed,
when the first University in Europe appeared,
his thought was told to people to people.
But, in 16th or 17th century, when Gallireo and Newton
made contemporaly science,
people started thinking about cosmo for the first time after Aristle.
That means people finally started studying cosmo
scientifically. After 400 or 500 years passed,
finally we are getting closer to the answer of birth of cosmo
and its structure. Using these knowledge,
we are now able to utilize science
for various purposes thanks to Aristle.
However, well-being Aristle believed the most important
and biggest problem
has never been tackled scientifically
at all.
So people is
still studying various models and theory
about well being.