Moreover, about happiness,
Japanese constitution
states in its 13rd sentence.
Mr. Kono, have you ever had
opportunities to think about
happiness or well-being
in academic place
like high school
or university.
No, I have never had
opportunities to think about it
explicitly
I think.
You have been educated,
And I also attended schools,
but I also have never
had chance
to think about well-being
in junior high school,
high school, and university
at all. But
as we have seen,
a mission of tokyo
institution of industory
code of conduct in conference
states well-being
clearly in them.
And Aristole also
identifies it is important,
and japanese constitution
clearly mention it,
we have never thought about
well-being.
As you say,
We can see the word
"happiness" itself
in many places today.
Actually, the word
"well-being" is
noticed around the world.
For example,
the Pope published
the 10 clues to be happier,
many magazines are
interested in
well-being.
But when I start thinking
about well-being,
I realize
it is a little bit complicated.
Especially, when we pick up
Japan as an example,
it seems strange for me.
How about you, Mr. Kono.
What do you think about Japan.
for security, its power,
hospitality..
What do you think.
I personally think
Japan is comfortable
country to live,
Personally.
Our GDP is the third highest
followed America and China.
Japan is very
economically powerful,
and safe, and clean.
I have visited many
countries and cities
for the purpose of my business
Japan is really good to live.
But Leicester University
in Great Britain
in 2006, made world
happiness map,
according to the map,
Japan ranked at 90th
in the world.
90th... (laughing)
Yes, 90th. what do you think.
Don't you think it is strange.
(laughing)
OECD, which many
countries belong
to economic development,
international organization
sees countries through GDP,
which is macro
index, but
currently, they use
well-being indicators.
Strangely, OECD does not
make rankings about it unlike
the Lecester University.
But they shows
various items, like
income, housing,
and employment.
they research the average,
and how is each country
in OECD.
This is what they do.
They also have some
more interesteing,
This is very interesting,
but what I want you to see is
satisfaction of life.
Most countries in OECD are
developed countries,
so 59% of people
are satisfied with their life.
Though Japanese is
satisfied just only 40%.
This is weird.
Moreover,
Many people taking this course,
their parents
or
their grand parents,
they have worked for
the country hard
thanks to those effort,
and thanks to researchers in
Tokyo Institutions of Industory,
Thanks to everything
I mentioned,
Japan has been becoming rich.
blue line in this figure,
is about Japanese GDP.
it always increases, that is,
Japan becomes rich.
it shows.
However, satisfaction of life
orange line shows it,
it decreases.
Strange.
Aeconomist Easterlin
found out and he named it
Paradox of Easterlin.
It means
richer people become,
poorer their satisfaction
of life is.
This is paradox.
Yes.
In addition, the rate of
suiceide in Japan is
high compared to other
developed countries.
Japan is safe and clean, though,
poor satisfaction of life and
many people kill themselves.
it is strange.
And another data says,
the data is from
Japanese government,
richness of stuff or
richness of heart,
which is more important
the government asks Japanese
people every year
Unitil 1980, richness of
stuff isb more important
for them than richness of heart.
People think.
However, after 1980,
people think richness
of heart is
more important.
How about you, Mr. Kono.
Which do you think
it is more important for you.
I think, as you think,
richness of heart is
more important
even though we become
economically powerful.
(laughing)
I see.
Then, hou about
money or hapiness.
To become happier,
Do you think money is important.
If you do not have money,
you cannot get stuff
and become unhappy,
so, I think Money is important.
(laughing)
when I am asked to choose one,
I cannot choose actually.
Many people think
they need money
to be happy,
but many research shows
money, hapiness,
and satisfaction
do not relate to
each other much.
This is a result of statics
conducted in America ,
yearly income 35,000 dollers,
if we say 1 doller is worth 100 yen,
people who get less than
3,500,000 yen have
lower happiness in America.
However, income is 35,000
doller to 50,000 doller,
in short, even if your income
improve 35,000 to 50,000 dollers,
5,000,000yen to 10,000,000yen,
or over 10,000,000 yen,
hapiness is not improved much.
at least this data says.
Other studies shows
however, other result,
they conclude
we can see the relationship
between money and hapiness
a little bit,
So actually,
the studies are still going.
Let's see
how American people
answered
when they are asked,
this is multiple choice
questions though,
First,
this is the item
most people chose,
relationship with their children
Their children make
them happier,
77% of people chose it.
And friendship makes
them happier,
when they contribute to someone,
75% of people chose them.
4th is about husband or wife.
Or relationship with
their lover.
This makes people happier,
74 % of people chose it.
So first 4 items are important
when we consider
hapiness
first 4 items are what I
introduced now.
The answer is the relationships
among people
not money or stuff.
This is the answer.
How were these studies about
hapiness or well-being
started.
Of course,
studies about hapiness
is made long time ago,
era of Aristole,
or further before
in many countries or cultures.
Martin Segman is the first
person who started it
scientifically. He is an
psychologist in America.
He is a professor in the
University of Pensylvania
He is an experimental
psychologist.
He is a chairman in American
Psychology Association.
He was elected by
three times vote from
the second applicant,
then he was elected
as a chairman.
American Psychological
Asscociation
is the biggest asscociation
both in America and
in the world.
Professor Segliman
will have to
decide which way
psychology to go
in the future.
He had to state that.
what do you think
Professor Segliman said.
He said various things though,
in his keynote,
what he said is
A Psychology in America
contributed to
patients who awere told
never be cured
were told never be cured,
and made manuals to diagnose
people who have mental problems,
That is great,
he said.
And Professor Segliman continues
people who have mental
issue are at most
20-30 percent,
the rest of 70% live healthier
like Mr. Kono,
Psychology ishould
be for hose 70%
can live better,
we should use
intervention,
this is a technical term,
we should use intervention for
helthy people to live better.
He proposed. Professor Segliman
stated he named it
positive psychology
to people, then
The history of positive
psychology
has officially
started.