Engineers' ethics (1)
It is not easy to define
what is engineers' ethics,
because 'engineer's ethics',
engineers', and 'ethics',
each of these
three terms has
many different meanings.
To approach how we can
define 'engineer's ethics',
we will first look at a
couple of basic definitions.
Let's start with the
term 'ethics'.
A world authority
in this field,
Michael Davis,
claims that 'ethics',
in general,
can be defined
by three meanings:
First, 'ethics', as its
origin derives from
the Greek word 'ethos',
or 'customs and usage',
'ethics' is defined as
customs and usages
in a certain geographical
or cultural area. Second,
'ethics' means a
body of codes
of behavior in a
social group.
In this course, we pay
particular attention on this
second definition. Thirdly,
'ethics' is a discipline
that scholarly describes and
interprets the codes
of behavior
in a social group.
In addition to
this definition of 'ethics'
by Michael Davis,
there are many
other definitions of
the term.
The shortest definition
I have found is that
by Oliver A. Johnson.
Johnson defined
'ethics' as 'the
science of conduct.'
Indeed, 'the science
of conduct'
is a huge subject that
has been discussed
by numerous scholars since
the time of ancient Greek.
Looking back the history
of the studies on ethics,
scholars have considered
mainly two questions:
One is"what is
good, or bad?",
and the other is
"what is right or wrong?"
These two problems were
examined by ethics as
scholarly practice.
However,
no one has ever succeeded
in propounding the one
and only definition
that can be
universally agreed.
Still,
we know that there
are at least
three different approaches
to answer the question:
Firstly, there's
the 'Virtue Ethics'
represented by Aristotle.
Secondly, the 'Dentology',
represented by
Immanuel Kant,
focuses on the
conduct itself.
Thirdly, the
'Utilitarian Ethics',
whose slogan 'the greatest
happiness of the greatest
number'
you may also have
heard of once,
aims at the results
of conduct,
thus called as
utilitarianism.
So, these are
the three basic viewpoints
on the ethics in the West.
Now, how do we define
ethics in Japan?
Let's look at a Japanese
dictionary definition.
It defines ethics as
'the path of human
ethics (Jin-rin), or
the normative principle of
practical morality.
But what is 'Jin-rin', or
'the path of human ethics'?
The dictionary defines
'Jin-rin' as
'the public order and
discipline
among people, or the path
you should follow as
a human.'
This sound still too vague
like a puzzling Zen riddles.
So, let us think about
that 'ethics' is a
synonym for 'morality'.
In the dictionary,
'morality' is defined as
'the path that people
should take',
and further it defines
morality
and ethics are 'the body of
norms that is generally
recognized
by a social group and its
members
as criteria for
judging a person
or his/her conducts
to other members
whether the person or
conducts are
good or bad to the society.'
Sounds a little more
understandable.
As we have seen,
there are many
other different definitions
of the term 'ethics'.
In this course,
rather than borrowing
somebody else's definitions,
I will use my own
definition.
I define 'ethics' as
follows:
'Ethics is a whole body of
normative system that
functions as criteria
in a social group for
judging value
of conducts, between
good and evil, or
right and wrong.' It also
means 'intellectual
practices
of continuous examination on
the system.'