So, what is positive psychology.
what on earth is positive psychology.
I know there are many definitions of it,though,
here is a definition, Professor Peggy Khan
In the University of Melborn,
actually he is a friend of mine.
Here, I can see more definition other than him.
His definition says positive psychology is that
it finds factors for prosperity of individuals or communities
and how people do to promote these factors.
We can find
scientific studies the most important thing
in his definition.
Science is important.
well-being that philosophers ,religionists,
and literary persons had insisted,
is well-living, but I think it is not true.
True meaning of positive psychology is
to study well-being scientifically.
This is the correct definition.
And, here is slides made by
Professor. Khan,
what positive psychology tells us is
to switch our perspectives.
Previous psychology
only helps people who have mental issues,
and its objective is to kill the problems they have,
that is to make a situation problem-free.
This is previous psychology.
But,
on the other hand, positive psychology is
meant for healthy people to live better.
Positive psychology requires
scientific studies in order to help people's life to be better.
So what is
the objectives of positive psychology.
What are those.
Does it mean that people become positive
and live  vigorously?
Some people thinks like that
though,
I think a goal of positive psychology is
not limited to emotion, such as
fun, happy, confortable. Not so simple.
Neither is just poitive thinking.
To define its goal in Japanese is a little difficult
though,
often said this is
flourish, not just hapiness.
Flourish is.
Flourish means,
needless to say, it includes
feelings like happy and fun,
but in addition, flourish implies the meanings that
I live fully, I am a part of the world,
I contribute to someone,
Flourish implies people live with these potential
all.
I believe this is the true meaning of flourish.
Flourish goes toward positive psychology.
The goal is positive psychology.
But
it is hard to find
correct corresponding words in Japanese.
"Hanei(prosperity)" sounds odd for me, it is the closest word in Japanese, though.
(laughing)
I think it's totally different from flourish in English.
Professor. Peggy Khan says,
in his slides,
let's say these plants are
people.
People live vigorously
this is the meaning of flourish.
But sadly,
this is what happens in Japan.
they are dead.
people are always alone, even when they are in the train,
they gaze their smartphones, they never talk to someone,
they seem introvert persons.
Anyway, positive psychology has
changed previous psychology
to more hapiness models.
While previous psychologists made a manual
for people having mental issues and disabilities
to diagnose them, positive psychologists thought
what are strengths and good point of people,
across countries, what characters or attitudes
people will be respected, like virtue.
Or, what are strengths of character.
These are the manual they have made.
So, let me repeat the important things he
it was changed from pathological model to
hapiness model.
Today, so called fuctional MRI, MEG, devices, which can image
various aspects of our brain
has appeared.
neuro science is also developing,
positive psychologists work with scientists who
study neuro science.
This is brand-new work.
For example, a research announced
in The University of Tokyo a few years ago,
showed where brain processes satisfaction
for the first time.
A research announced in the University of Kyoto
shows where is the mental basis in the brain
when people feel happy. These are outcomes of the work.
People started to study well-being
scientifically,
and some outcomes has just appeared now,
but how these outcomes are used,
only in academic study.
No No, they are used
in various purposes.
For example, U.S. army uses them
not only for their army,
but also for families of their army,
and their relatives.
Not only for physical fitness
but also for emotional fitness.
And for social fitness,
for fitness of family relation
for spiritual fitness, as well.
They call these fitness
comprehensive soldier fitness
as one thing
They hold a program to improve their cpmprehensive soldier fitness
to all people related to army.
Who made the program is
Seligman.