How to act as engineer
on the site (3)
Without any major
development,
the launch day
came.
A cold wave and
temperature drop were
forecast on the very day.
Before examining
the situation
of the day before,
we will look at
a few more facts.
Why did NASA decide
to carry out
the launching?
In the beginning,
NASA estimated
the space shuttle project
would yield profits.
However,
limited number of times of
for launching caused a
delay in the project.
Another factor was
the emerging rivalries
in Europe,
who had similar space
shuttle projects.
Furthermore,
due to the delay
in progress,
the American Congress began
to question the
NASA's project,
as it didn't give
sufficient results
corresponding the
enormous investment.
To appeal the Congress,
in 1986, NASA had a
congested plan of launching,
such as a space probe for
examination of Halley's Comet.
The biggest reason
for NASA
to carry out the
launching of Challenger
is said to be
Reagan's intention.
To evade public criticism
against his
education policy,
Reagan wanted to include
a civilian
schoolteacher McAuliffe
as a Challenger
crew member,
making her the first teacher
who gave a class
for children
from the space.
In his draft of the State
of the Union address,
Reagan was celebrating
McAuliffe's achievement
and the arrival of new era.
The President's
political intention was
a major cause of the
launching of Challenger.
Could you explain about
the situation the day
before the launch?
Yes. It was a
drastic evening.
Forecasts for the time of
launching in the night
predicted an unusually
low-temperature,
- 1℃.
It was far beyond the
lowest temperature
at the preceding
launchings.
Knowing the forecast,
Mr. Boisjoly and his team
firmly believed that
this cold temperature would
reduce the durability
of O-rings,
threatening the
lives of crews.
They visited the vice
president engineer,
Land, and claimed
to postpone
the launching.
Convinced by the team,
Land decided to suggest
the postponement to NASA.
To launch the Challenger,
approvals from not only
the Morton-Thiokol
but from all the involved
companies were needed.
In principle, therefore,
if the Morton-Thiokol would
have withdrawn
their approval,
the launching
were cancelled.
At the teleconference
on the evening,
Morton-Thiokol discussed
the weather conditions
and their concern
about the O-rings
with NASA managers
from Kennedy Space Center
and Marshall Space
Flight Center.
The data on the correlation
between the temperature
and rubber's resilience
provided by Mr. Boisjoly's team,
however,
showed only the cases
with flaws and
did not include
those without flaws,
failing in proving
the exact condition
under which a flaw
can be unavoidable.
When Morton-Thiokol Inc.
asked for some time
to review their data,
and five-minutes
of suspension
of the conference
was approved.
In the off-line
internal meeting
within Morton Thiokol,
which lasted over 30 mins,
Mr. Boisjoly and Thompson
re-expressed
their concern to
the managements.
They opposed the launch
and claimed its
postponement.
However, the managers
from NASA,
including a legend-engineer
George Hardy
and the space shuttle solid
rocket booster program manager,
Larry Mulloy,
clearly expressed
unpleasant feelings
against Morton-Thiokol.
The provided data was not
as strong and decisive
as to prove the urgent
need of postponement.
These factors affected
the decision-making process of
the management of
Morton-Thiokol.
Eventually,
as the discussion
was stuck,
the Morton-Thiokol's
Senior Vice President
of Operations, J. Mason,
started to shout
impatiently
at other three
managements
at the meeting, C. Wiggins,
J. Kilminster
and Lund; asking,
"Am I the only one
who wants to launch?"
Confronting Mason's anger
against the
postponement,
Wiggins and Kilminster
were convinced
that they needed to make
a management judgment
and agreed to launch
as scheduled.
Lund, who was opposing
to the bitter end,
withdrew his opposition
when Mason, the vice
president of operations,
shouted at him:
"It is time to take off
your engineering hat
and put on your
management hat."
Today this phrase
is infamous,
unfortunately.
Mason's word was decisive,
and Lund decided to vote
to approve the launch,
making the 4 affirmative vote
against 0 negative vote.
After this discussion,
Morton-Thiokol Inc.
obtained the consent
for the launch.
Morton-Thiokol submitted
the agreement
document to NASA,
which confirmed the
safety of rooster
for a launch and
signed by Wilkinson,
who was in charge of
the booster locket project.
Upon submission
of Morton-Thiokol's
agreement,
the permission was
finally given
for the launch of the Challenger
as it was originally
scheduled.
In this way,
Morton-Thiokol Inc.
ended up
approving the launch.
What would you do,
if you were Mr. Boisjoly?
1) Respect the final
management judgment,
and simply wish the O-rings
seal tightly under the
low air temperature.
2) Report the
management of NASA
that the safety
is under threat;
3) Make notice to the
family of crew members
about the potential
risk of safety;
4) Make public announcement
via mass media
to claim for
postponement of a launch
under cold-temperature;
5) Take some other actions.