I am sorry , but can I ask you a question again.
Have you ever seen this picture.
Yes,
in the textbook.
I see.
Actually I have never seen the actual work.
This is the work of Rafaello
who is epic artist in Renaissance
it is in Batican.
simplly,
I might simplificate it too much, though
People in Runaissance
thought
wisdom of humankind came from
ancient greece and Rome.
that was lost during middle ages.
and people try to recover it
to bring it back to Europe
they try to bring back glorious wisdom
to Europe again.
This is what they wanted
to do.
An famouse artist Raffaelo
made
he was also a philosophier
who made new philosophy in Rome era
or in ancient Greece.
For example, he wrote
scientists
too in his pictures.
Pythagoras and
Archmedes
are drew in his pictures.
He also draw himselves
in his picture
for people in Runaissance
they believe people in his picture
made wisdom.
There are two people
who found wisdom
These are the two
Do you know who they are
I remember one is Plato pointing out ceiling, and
Aristole pointing out ground,
Maybe.
Plato shows idea,
and points out ceiling where idea is.
He positions himself at naturalism.
On the other hand, Aristlo points out ground
to tell us to see real.
So
an eldery in the left is Plato,
and the right one is Aristole
who is the most superior disciple of Plato.
A book Plato has is
about his late discussion.
that is, "Timaios" written
for nature world.
A book Aristole has is
"Ethica"
sometimes called Ethics
or Ethic
It is about his ethics
actually he did not write the book by himself,
his disciples wrote it
In Japanese, it is named after his son's name,
that is, Nicomachum ethics.
Its theme is
eudimonia in Greece
The focus is put on
Eudimonia
Eudimonia is
translated in various way.
for example, flourishing,
prosperity, or happiness.
But
The most appropriate translation is
well-being I think.
For example, Aristole studied
physics, biology, astronomy,
and economics, politics
Metaphysiscs, and poems,
he studied variety of field,
and his disciples left
Aristole's thought in the book.
so, he is often regarded as
pioneer of various academic fields
today.
In 12th century,  Europe had the first university
and developed it
what was taught there was scholatic philosophy,
which binded the philosophy of Aristole
with Christ.
In this way, person who is symbolized as wisdom of western
that is, thought of Aristole, this is ethics
and well-being.
Aristole refers to
his own thought in various way
An important thing is
called superative goodness,
it is to think what means living better,
that is, it is well-being.