Associations or parties related to
engineer ethics around the world
have their ethic manuals, as we have seen,
the manuals says what they have to focuse on in them.
clearly.
In the first part of the manuals,
they refer to principle like this slide
here is a manual made by
National Society of Professional Engineers
NSPE in America,
other associations also have similar
principle as the associations in America.
Pronciple is about
engineers have to focus on
public safety, health, and welfare
when they work as engineers. it is expressed as hold paramount
as you know,
in English.
As I told,
Safety and health have been discussed
much, I think thats's enough.
some people majors in Safety engineering.
but, as as written in the constitution,
As  safety and health,
it is imoortant to put on focus
on welfare, or well-being
in English.
engineers have never thought about
welfare or well-being much,
and we expertise of engineer ethics also have
never thought about it much.
I realized.
Welfare is mentioned
in the other parts, too.
I agree, this is a manual in
Japan academic conference, which is
an organization for researchers,
it says about their code of conductions in it.
it is about responsibility for researchers.
This is the first line. The responsibility of researchers is
to guarantee qualities of knowledge and techniques they produce,
Also, to contribute to health and welfare
for human beings
through their experience, knowledge, and techniques.
This is clearly stated
in it. By the way Mr. Kono,
Tokyo institute of industry, which we belong
has a mission.
Do you know what it is.
Excuse me, a mission...
Yes, a mission.
I have no idea at all.I'm so shame.
it is
writen in rule book of our organization,
it clearly states
our purpose and mission.
We can see some sentences in it though,
in the first part and last part of it,
to contribute to welfare is our purpose and
mission. This is the reason our institute exists.
We can see the words "welfare" everywhere
or "well-being",
many people say they are important,
as our examples shows,
they say welfare is important,
however, we have never discussed
well-being at all.
Mr. Kono is still new to our institution though,
in our institution,
have you ever had opportunities
to talk about welfare.
No, never.
I see.
How well-being relates to
ethics.
Good question.
Thanks.
Ethics is intended to think about
well-being originally.
As I told,
well-being is translated into welfarein Japanese,
but sometimes,
it is translated into happiness.
anyway, it implies lots of meanings,
and it is interepret as many ways.
Now, I define well-being means
living better
to avoid confusion.