That means that air pollution had become
a serious problem even in Japan at that time,
which led to various regulations.
In 1966, the Ministry of Transportation
had committed to keeping carbon monoxide levels
to 3% or less. Then, in 1967,
The Environmental Pollution Prevention Act​, and in 1968,
the Air Pollution Control Law was enacted.
In 1970, there was an incident in Tokyo involving
a female high school student who collapsed during gym class,
which raised widespread awareness about
so-called photochemical smog.
Now, air pollution from car exhaust may have been
a serious problem in Japan at that time,
but the situation in the US was even worse.
In 1970, the US passed a law called
the Clean Air Act Amendments,
also known as the Muskie Act,
after Senator Muskie, who drafted it.
There was a Clean Air Act of 1963,
but the new law had significantly revised it.
It was an extremely strict law that demanded
a 90% decrease in the concentration of harmful substances
like the carbon monoxide in car exhaust—that is,
1/10 of the 1970 level—in 5 years’ time.
This regulation gave the car companies of the time—
known in the US as the Big Three—
it sent shock waves throughout the auto industry.
As you can imagine, the Big Three that I just mentioned—
the industry—responded in a chorus of opposition,
saying that it was technically impossible.
So, how do you think Sōichiro HONDA viewed
the enactment of the Muskie Act in the US?
This is where it gets interesting.
Mr. Honda saw it as a business opportunity.
This is because, even though Honda was selling
kei-cars (light cars) at the time,
those kei-cars caused some accidents that resulted in
their drivers’ deaths. The company was
taken to court under the accusation that
Honda’s faulty cars were to blame for the accidents.
As a result, Honda’s revenues hit a major slump.
It was then that Mr. Honda realized that
if he could succeed in developing the low-emission engines
that the world’s leading automakers had deemed impossible,
then Honda would be able to rub shoulders with
other automakers. So, Mr. Honda came to oversee
the development of a low-emission engine
as a business opportunity, without any connection to
environmental values. In February 1971,
he announced that it would be possible to develop
an engine that met the requirements of
the Muskie Act, but in reality,
this was nowhere near true at the time. (laughs)
(laughs)
Now, Sōichiro HONDA was very close with his
team of young engineers, who called him Pops.
He was always on the factory floor with them,
extolling the joys of making things with your own two hands.
But at this point, Mr. Honda thought about what to do
not as an engineer, but as a manager.
And as a manager, he decided that, in order to
save the company he built from the crisis
it had found itself in, he would announce
the development of a new engine
that met the requirements of the Muskie Act.
At the time, people were already thinking
about the role of engineers,
given that it was not solely Honda’s prerogative,
but rather the entire auto industry’s prerogative,
to support engineers working on the project
and to combat air pollution. That is, ask yourself
what you ought to do as an engineer, and act accordingly—
one of the ethical principles emphasized in this course.
For the engineers who toiled night and day
in Honda’s rigorous R&D environment
to help make the project a success,
the development of the CVCC engine was certainly
an important event that shaped Honda’s destiny.
However, even more than that,
it is thought that a major factor
in the project’s success was
the belief that the development of a low-emission engine
that meets the requirements of the Muskie Act
was what engineers can and must do for society.
This sense of duty is expressed by the words of
a man named Sho ISHIZUYA,
who belonged to an air pollution research lab:
“Let’s leave clear, blue skies for our children.”
“Clear skies for our children”
was the vision and sense of mission
behind future development projects,
which would be overseen
not by Sōichiro HONDA himself,
but by a leader named Mr. Tadashi KUME,
who was 39 at the time and
would later become the president of Honda.
So, projects like those that aim to, say,
make an engine that meets requirements
thought to be impossible by other companies,
succeed because the members share a vision
that project is not about the company,
but rather about the role of engineers in society.
That’s why the projects would succeed:
There was a shared set of values
regarding the purpose of technological development.