Space Shuttle Challenger
disaster (1) as a lesson of
engineer's ethics
In this lecture,
we will examine the case of
Space Shuttle Challenger
disaster,
which happened in
January 1986.
This is a highly significant
case
for the matter of engineer's
ethics,
and is discussed on
almost every textbooks.
As the accident was
witnessed
by people all over the whole
world,
it triggered people
to recognize the necessity
of
ethics of engineers and
corporations.
This is, indeed,
a classical case study of
engineer's ethics.
So let us examine the most
famous case.
I would like you to think
about this case,
not from a viewpoint of a
critic or
a non-participant observer,
but from a viewpoint of an
engineer,
who was responsible for
the decision-making process
of the project.
The engineers who took part
in this project and their
values
will be further discussed
in following lectures,
so please listen to the
discussion carefully,
and think about
who are the stakeholder
in this case,
to what kinds of values
these stakeholders place
greatest importance.