Stakeholders in the
case of Challenger
Now, who were the
stakeholders
in the case of space
shuttle Challenger?
The stakeholders in
the case included
NASA, Morton-Thiokol.
More precisely,
Larry Mulloy of NASA, and
engineers and managements
of the Morton-Thiokol,
namely Boisjoly,
Mason, and Lund,
as well as crew members of
Challenger including McAuliffe.
Furthermore, families
of crew members
and school children
of McAuliffe.
President Reagan,
the government
and related ministries
of United States
were also stakeholder.
The list goes on:
municipal government in
Utah, local residents,
employees and their families
of the Morton-Thiokol,
its subcontractors, and
other contractors of NASA
and their employees
and their families.
In a broader context,
engineers and
developers of the space
developments in other countries,
are also stakeholders.
Of course American citizen
were stakeholders, too.
Especially we should
note the end-users,
namely crewmembers were
weak stakeholders.
We should also note that
invisible stakeholders who were
not directly involved in the
explosion,
such as family members of
the crewmembers,
were actually weak stakeholders
affected by the incident quite
directly.
Furthermore, it was a
disaster
occurred to such a huge
project of
great expectations and hope,
and there were many
other stakeholders
affected by it at
different levels.
Despite of their
invisibility,
it is still possible that
the disaster influenced on
their life-choices.