The topic I'd like to introduce now is
thinking about the ethics of science and engineering
on four different levels.
I have spoken on the subject of ethics of science and engineering
to a number of people.
I've discussed it extensively.
It's a subject that really gets people talking.
I've had many interesting discussions and
participants presented a variety of opinions
but it would often get to the point when
I felt there was a mismatch in our perspectives.
This made me think about
the four different levels concerning ethics.
When people discuss ethics, each speaking on a different level
they will only be at cross purposes.
This is the conclusion I've come to.
First, we have engineers
or scientists. We focus on individuals.
Why did this or that person make a particular decision?
Think from their point of view.
Was the decision they made right?
This is what we call
micro-ethics.
Looking at ethics from the point of view of
the relationship between science and society
when making decisions
is referred to as macro-ethics.
So we have micro-ethics
with an individual focus
and macro-ethics where we look at
the bigger picture and role of science in the society.
These are two major levels.
But, especially in Japan...
Apart from micro- and macro- ethics
there is an additional, organisational level.
This applies to engineers in particular.
It's very common to be part of an organisation.
So we have this meso-ethics level in between micro and macro.
I think it's easy to think about it in this way.
But there is yet another level.
It's rarely brought up.
On the fourth level, we look at the nature of science itself.
And what technology is.
What purpose do they serve?
On this level we ask more
metaphysical questions.
This I call meta-level ethics.
So we have meta-, macro-, mezo- and micro-ethics.
When you are aware of these four levels
and think about ethics within this framework
you start realising, oh he's talking on the micro-ethics level.
And now I'm talking about macro-ethics.
It becomes easier for you to engage in a discussion
on the same plane.