How to act as engineer on
the site ? (1)
The following part
of this lecture will be left
to Mr. Kono.
The interview we had
with Mr. Boisjoly in 2003
will give an account of
his action at the accident.
The interview is
also available in text
on our website.
So, Mr. Kono,
please start.
Okay. We'll examine
the details of
the Challenger case
in four stages,
from January 1985
to the accident.
What kind of action
would you take,
if you were Mr. Mr. Boisjoly?
Stage A: In January 1985, in
the post-flight investigation
of the Discovery, an engineer
of the Morton-Thiokol
Mr. Mr. Boisjoly, found out
the evidence
that the burning gas blew
by the primary O-ring.
What would you do?
There are several
possible actions:
1) Examine the problem by
yourself more in detail,
without consulting
anyone else;
2) Consult your fellow
engineers;
3) Consult your
immediate boss;
4) Express your concern
directly to the chief
engineer executive,
or the vice-president of
the Morton-Thiokol
responsible for engineering;
5) Express your concern
directly to the
company's CEO;
6) Contact to the
consultation desk
at the Morton-Thiokol
or NASA (if any);
7) Form a private team
of professionals
in the company to
find a solution
before proposing it
to your boss;
8) Report the evidence to
an external organization;
9) Provide the information
to mass-media;
10) Do nothing special;
11) Take some other actions.
As you see, there are many
possible actions
you could take.
If you were Mr. Boisjoly,
what would you do, when,
one year before the
Challenger's disaster,
you found out the flaw
with the O-ring?
What is the value at stake
at this first stage?
Who are the stakeholders?
In Mr. Boisjoly's case,
upon finding the flaw,
he consulted his
immediate boss.
Recognized the problem
with field joint,
he observed the
low-temperature
at the Discovery's launch
and hypothesized that
the temperature may
affect O-rings sealing.
He then reported this to
his boss, inaudible.
The boss directed Mr. Boisjoly
to visit the Marshall
Space Flight Center
to report his hypothesis
to the members of NASA.
Despite Mr. Boisjoly's
report on the relation
between the temperature and
rubber's elasticity,
NASA, requested Mr. Boisjoly
not to stress his
observation,
claiming it wouldn't be cold
at the next launch
planned in Florida
in April following year.
Stage B: What kind of action
would you take,
if you would be
requested by NASA
not to stress your
observation?
Let me list possible
options:
1) Accept NASA's assumption
and request.
As NASA is your
important client,
you won't tell your
observation
beyond your fellow
engineers;
2) Irrelevant to the air
temperature of the scheduled
day of launch,
it is an urgent
matter of safety.
You will write a report to
criticize the NASA's response
and hand it to your boss or
the vice-president
who is responsible for
engineering;
3) A launch under
low-temperature
seems less possible,
but this is still
a grave matter of safety.
You will accept the
NASA's request,
but ask your boss
to form a special team
to investigate the problem;
4) Form an investigation
team yourself
with your fellow
engineers and staff
in related fields including
administrators
and PR office, examine
possible effects
that can be caused
by an accident,
and propose a measure that
the corporation should take;
5) Contact the compliance
support desk
at Morton-Thiokol or
NASA, if there is any;
6) Report to an external
organization;
7) Take some other actions.
These are possible
actions you may take.
It should be noted here that
the appropriate action you
should take might differ,
depending on the
likelihood of an accident,
how it is threatening
and crucial.
For what happened to
Mr. Boisjoly next,
you should read his
interview report.