The Stakeholder
In the following part,
we will examine
the stakeholder in this case
study of Challenger disaster.
In his interview,
Mr. Boisjoly stressed
repeatedly that
safety is far more
important for engineers
than their belonging
corporations,
or even himself.
Indeed, many ethical
mission statements
of scientific societies
and associations,
which write the important
value for engineers,
clearly state that
engineers must place
the top priority
on the value of
public safety,
health, and welfare.
In ethical policies, it is
stipulated for example,
that an engineer should take
responsibility for the
credibility
of the products'safety
he/she developed.
In this regard,
Mr. Boisjoly's strong
opposition to launch
was following the engineer's
ethics and policy.
At the same time, however,
the ethical statement
also requires
allegiance of engineers
to their employers
and clients.
In the case of Challenger,
the employer was
Morton-Thiokol Inc.
and the client was NASA.
Therefore, it was also
Mr. Boisjoly's obligation
to avoid conflict with his
employer and client,
and follow their directions.
Now, how do you judge
when such a conflict
between values arises?
We will examine
the ethical
decision-making process
to the detail in
the lecture 3.
For now, let me point out a
few examples.
What should engineers do
to make the best action
when you confront with
various ethical problems?
In the ethical
decision-making process,
it is essential for
engineers to consider
who would be affected
by your decision and
conducts.
To which extend you
could recognize
potential organizations
and events
that might be influenced by
your ethical decision,
is highly important.
Generally,
stakeholders include,
for example, yourself,
your family,
users, organizations
you belong to,
such as corporation
or a research institute,
your colleagues and
their families,
outside corporations in contract
with your organizations,
such as subcontractors
and suppliers
people belong to these
corporations,
the government and its
ministries and other agencies,
municipalities and
local residents,
related scientific
associations, and mass-media,
these are all stakeholders.
Thus, these persons and
organizations,
who may influence your
decision-making,
as well as those who may
be influenced by
your decision-making
and conducts,
directly or indirectly,
are called 'stakeholder'.
'Stakeholder' is a
significant notion
of engineer's ethics.
In Japanese, stakeholder is
often translated as
'interested parties
and persons'.
You might think
this means
financial interest,
but stakeholders are
not limited to
financial profit and loss.
This may lead
misunderstandings of
the notion and narrow
our discussion.
In this course, therefore,
we will use the
English word,
'stakeholder'.
In short, 'stakeholder'
should be defined as
someone/something who
may influence,
directly or indirectly,
on your ethical
decision-making and conducts
as well as those
who may be affected
by the decision and
conducts.
How can we distinguish
and specify
all the stakeholders we should
consider appropriately?
It's a good question.
There are several points
you should consider.
First, you should note that
there are strong stakeholders
and weak stakeholders.
For instance, for engineers,
product users and
clients are
important stakeholders.
They are weak stakeholders,
as they depend on
engineers and makers
in terms of the safety
of the products they use.
An example: engineers who design
aircrafts and passengers.
To understand to whom
you are responsible for,
it is important for
engineers
to consider weak
stakeholders.
Secondly, you
should note that
there are visible and
invisible stakeholders.
For instance, families
of users are
relatively invisible
stakeholders,
however, they should be
considered as well.
Here's another example:
the health hazard
caused by asbestos.
In this case, manufacture
of building materials
should consider stakeholders
beyond physical
or temporal proximity.
People living in
remote areas
and future users are
both your stakeholder.
By becoming aware of
the existence
of invisible stakeholders,
engineers are able to
recognize the stakeholders
properly and thoroughly.
When confronted with
a trouble,
we tend to be affected by
immediate problems.
We then tend to
consider only
visible, strong stakeholders
such as those in your
own organization.
This narrows your
perspective
and results in your failing
to make proper ethical
decision-making.
To avoid this,
it is essential for you
to carefully consider weak,
invisible stakeholders.