Value and Ethical Codes
for Engineers
The 7 Steps guide is a
general guideline
for ethical decision-making.
It is not only for
engineers, but also
for broader range of people
in various occupations.
However, as we have discussed
in previous lesson,
there's a special requirement
for engineering ethics:
engineers must
recognize new values
created by innovative
technologies and
balance it with
existing values.
Now, what are the
values that
engineers should
consider particularly?
There are ethics
tests designed
especially for professions.
They examine the
adequacy of an action
an engineer is
about to take,
in light of the
ethical values
that are particularly important
for engineering profession.
Strictly speaking, what
ethical values engineers
should put particular
emphasis should be discussed
not only by engineers but also
with all the stakeholders
including end-users
who benefit
from the technological
development.
Unfortunately,
there is no such a
discussion platform
at this moment.
Instead, the ethical
codes propounded
by the scientific societies
and associations
play that part.
In Europe and especially in
the United States,
engineers' ethical values
are often explained
by the social
contract model.
The social contract model is
closely related to the
European university system
established in the
12th century
and based on the notion of
'learned profession'.
Traditionally, European
societies acknowledged
and fostered the
'learned profession'
with highly professional
knowledge and
skills such as priests,
medical doctors,
and lawyers.
Like these traditional
professions, engineers tried
to build and maintain a
relationship of trust
with society so that
they would achieve
higher social recognition.
To be acknowledged as
profession,
the group needs to state
a mission statement to
the society.
So, like the Hippocratic
Oath for the physicians,
associations of engineers
compounded an oath
to state to what kinds of
values they serve.
Having and observing an
ethical code was a basic need
to be respected as
profession in a society.
So, engineers considered
what they should write
in the engineer's
ethical code.
There are many opinions
about ethical codes.
Indeed, philosopher John Radd
was skeptical of ethical codes.
Radd pointed out that
'ethic' is a notion
that evades universal
definition.
It is an open-ended concept
that has no one-and-only
definition.
Therefore, it is the
confusion of 'mathematical'
and 'ethical' solution to
find an answer
based on the ethical codes.
This oversimplifies the
observance of ethical codes
to achievement of moral
discipline.
Others consider the
ethical codes
not as rules but
rather as a guideline
that leads engineers
to make decisions.
The ethical codes are the
embodiment of knowledge
and experiences accumulated
by preceding engineers.
It serves as a proper
guideline for current
and prospective engineers
at their duties
on their decision-making
process.
The ethical codes play a
significant role
in that they encourage awareness
of the responsibilities
of engineering and
normalization
of engineer's ethical
conducts.
Other scholars, including
Michael Davis,
place put a far more greater
emphasis on ethical codes.
According to Davis, the
ethical codes should be
regarded as contract
between professions.
An ethical code is a
social contract
between profession
and society.
In consideration for
their fulfillment
of specialized services that
are essential for the health,
safety and well-being of
people and its society,
which cannot be performed by
other individuals,
the society gives high
reputations towards engineers
and grant substantial
autonomy to the profession.
To maintain this mutually
beneficial relationship,
profession needs to construct
a strict ethical code.
At the same time, ethical
codes are contract
between the professional
engineers,
which foster and enable
mutual cooperation
between professionals.
This mutual cooperation
between the professionals
makes it possible for them
to oppose bigger pressures
that you cannot
resist alone.
Ethical codes protect
individual engineers
from an undesired
pressure, for instance,
to force them to skip
some working procedure
to save financial costs.
Ethical code gives a
foundation for engineers
to protest against such
pressures
not only as moral
practitioners but also
as professionals with skills
and knowledge.
As a contract between
professionals,
composition of ethical code
is an embodiment
of the common ideals shared
by the members of profession,
or the oath they
swear each other.
The establishment and
observance of ethical codes are
autonomous behavior of
professionals.
While the understanding of
ethical code
as a social contract
emphasizes
the engineer's powerful
influence on the society,
ethical code as a contract
between professions stresses
the internal norm and standard
of the profession of engineers.
One focuses on the
external factors
and the other looks at
internal factors.
These two interpretations of
ethical codes are
not mutually exclusive,
rather complementary
to each other.
As we have seen, in short,
ethical codes have
different functions.
Let's have a brief look on
how engineering
associations' ethical codes
have been constructed.
In the United States, the first
ethical codes of engineering
was propounded in the 1910s
with a model
of ethical codes established
by physicians in 1847.
The American Institute of
Electrical Engineers
made the first engineering
codes of ethics in 1912.
The early codes of ethics
aimed at
achieving a high social status
approved to physicians.
Therefore, engineers were
treated as individual
professionals
who serve their clients
independently,
rather than as a mere
member of organization.
These early codes emphasized
professional ethics
of engineers
and stipulated values such
as allegiance, obedience,
and the professional skills.
After the WWII,
scientific societies
and associations revised
their ethical codes
of engineers for
several times.
In addition to engineer's
responsibility
for employers and clients,
their responsibility
for public began to be
recognized.
After a half an century,
the engineer's mission
for the public was
stipulated in the
ethical codes.
Furthermore, in 1974,
a union of scientific
associations
established the ethical
codes that gives priority
to the the engineer's
responsibility for public
over their responsibility
towards employers
and clients.
This code of ethics
for engineers
established by the National
Society of Professional
Engineers
was adopted by many other
societies and associations,
becoming a standard model
of such codes.
Next, we will examine
important values
stated in these code of
ethics for engineers.