Space Shuttle Challenger
disaster (2) --- as a lesson of
engineer's ethics
The disaster of space
shuttle Challenger occurred
on January 28, 1986,
in front of
the eyes of people all
over the world.
The space shuttle
Challenger broke apart and
exploded 73 seconds
after it was launched
from the Kennedy Space
Center in Florida.
Among the seven crew members
there was a civilian
teacher,
Christa McAuliffe,
who would have been
the first teacher in space.
All the seven crew members
died in the shuttle.
It was a disaster.
Actually, on the
very day of the launch,
the area of Florida was hit
by a record-breaking
cold wave.
The temperature at
the time of the launch
was 2.2℃ below freezing, which
was far below
the usual temperature in
this season in Florida.
The Challenger was launched
under these unusual conditions;
the air temperature was
lower than average
in previous launches by
good 10 degrees.
This unusual cold
temperature was
the reason that
caused the accident.
Look at the picture of
the Challenger.
The orbiter with delta wing
is equipped with
the main engine.
Atop the orbiter is
the external fuel tank
marked in red
to supply the main engine
with liquid fuel.
The external fuel
tank is equipped
with a solid-rocket booster
on each side,
which generate
the primary propulsion.
All the parts
excluding the
external fuel tank
will be collected
and reused.
The next slide illustrates
the solid-rocket booster.
Each part was produced
in a plant of the
Morton-Thiokol in Utah,
a corporation under contract
with the NASA, and
then assembled together at
the Kennedy Space
Center in Florida.
The field joint,
which joint several
parts together
has to airtight
to seal the hot,
high-pressure gasses.
The investigation of the
special commission
appointed by U.S.
President Ronald Regan,
concluded that
the accident was caused
by the hot gasses leaked
from the joint,
which ignited the
external fuel tank
and set off the explosion.
The field joints were sealed
with rubber O-rings.
However, the unusually
cold temperature
reduced elasticity
of the rubber,
and the O-rings failed
to fulfill the expected
sealing function.
To enhance the performance,
the joints were sealed
with two O-rings,
but the burning gas
melted them both
and reached the outside.
Actually, Morton-Thiokol
had recognized
the flaw in field joints
already in 1970's
at the developmental stage
of the shuttle.
In this lecture,
we will examine
the case of Challenger
from the perspective of
on-site engineer, Boisjoly.
Certainly, to give a
comprehensive analysis of
the case from science
historical
and technological
viewpoints,
closer examinations
on evidences
from both NASA
and Morton-Thiokol
are necessary.
In this lecture, however,
we will examine the case
from an educational point of view
for engineering ethics,
focusing especially on
Boisjoly's engagement
rather than
historical studies
of the case.