At last, in October 1972, Honda made an announcement
about their CVCC engine, which was designed to satisfy
the requirements of the Muskie Act.
In December of the same year,
it would undergo testing by the US EPA,
which formally announced in March 1973 that
the CVCC engine was compatible
with the Muskie Act.
Honda had thus achieved something
considered impossible by the Big Three
and other major automakers.
And not only that, Honda also shared
the technology with other automakers,
which was a huge leap forward
in the initiative to reduce emissions.
So that is why we can look up today
and see the blue sky that we do.
The Honda Civic, which used this engine,
succeeded worldwide because of its
fuel economy and environmental considerations,
and introduced the whole world to Honda’s
technological prowess. In 2000, the Civic
was the only Japanese entry in a readers’ poll
by the American Society of Automotive Engineers
of the most technologically advanced cars
of the 20th century.
The CVCC engine transformed what was
just another Japanese company into
the Honda that the world knows today.
Exactly. And at the time, I was
in between high school and college,
and for us, the Civic,
equipped with Honda’s CVCC engine,
was our dream car. Well, this period was
Sōichiro HONDA’s last years,
about which he has this to say:
“For me, the CVCC project was the ideal chance
to develop a low-emission engine would put me
on the map with the four leading automakers.
“But when young engineers spoke of the exhaust problem
not as a company issue, but rather as a problem
that the auto industry had a social responsibility
to solve, and insisted that this was their duty,
it opened my eyes and moved me deeply.
“Everyone has grown up so fast. We have
entered a new era that requires a new kind of
management, built upon new values like these
that have opened my eyes, and a fresh take
on the relationship between companies and society.”
This is how he felt. Soon after this,
Mr. Honda would pass the baton to his successor.
The development of the CVCC engine saved Honda
from its management crisis. But it would not have
been possible without the engineers’ belief
that it was the auto industry’s social responsibility
to “leave blue skies for our children.”
The CVCC engine is, for me, an excellent example,
that reflects the need to be aware of
environmental values; of the social responsibility
of companies and engineers; and of the fact that
the stakeholders of a technology
are not only its providers and users,
but the whole society and the next generation too.