As we have discussed before in this course, in ethics,
there is precautionary ethics,
which focuses on what you shouldn’t do,
and intentional ethics, which is about
considering what you should do
and acting accordingly. The discourse and teaching
of engineering ethics have so far tended to
emphasize the precautionary side, but going forward,
I have explained that we also need intentional ethics.
The story of the Honda Civic is a perfect example
of the positive results that decision-making
and behavior based on intentional ethics can have.
Exactly. So, Mr. Kōno often says that
engineers bear a special responsibility
but have you ever thought about the reason why?
In past lectures, we have talked about how
technology demands responsibility
because of the great influence it exerts
on modern society.
I’d like you to take a look at this next slide.
I have been researching and teaching
engineering ethics for over 20 years now,
and up until maybe the last 5 or 6 years or so,
I’ve used these three models to explain
why engineers have a special responsibility.
The first is the “Contract between
Profession and Company” model,
also called the social contract model.
The second is the “Social Experiment” model,
which says that technology changes society,
so in a sense, it’s an experiment.
And the third, which I have discussed
in various forms, is something called
the “mutual dependence” model.
They are written about in more detail
on the course website, which I’d
like you to read.
I believe these models are each
quite persuasive models.